# NICK REYNOLDS | NICKREYNOLDS.NET

SAN FRANCISCO, CA | PH: 425.241.1185 | E: ME@NICKREYNOLDS.NET

## **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer specializing in mobile development with experience at Facebook and Microsoft. Owner, team lead, and tech lead for multiple engineers and a product with millions of daily active users. Experience developing Android and Windows Phone mobile applications, desktop and web applications, web services, and improving reliability/performance. Interested in product development in mobile, wearable, home automation, augmented reality, home entertainment, and internet of things.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Queensland | QUEENSLAND, AUSTRALIA

Bachelor in Softare Engineering double major First class honors 2004-2007

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Facebook | MENLO PARK, CA

Tech Lead & Senior Softare Engineer - Messenger for Windows Phone Dec 2013 – Current

Designed, built and owned Messenger for Windows Phone, leading a team of 4-8 engineers.

Created dash to track daily reliablity, growth and performance.

Strategy owner, maintaining feature set with other platforms and tracking to specific goals.

Softare Engineer - Messenger for Android Sept 2012 – Dec 2013

Reduced send errors by 85% and improved send experience.

Worked many features including image sending, voice clips, 3.0 redesign, improved message bubbles, etc. Release manager for multiple releases.

Microsoft | BELLEVUE, WA

Softare Engineer II - Windows Phone Communications Apr 2011 – Jul 2012

Ported communication applications to Windows Phone 8 security model. Implemented phone number pasting

Implemented visual voicemail and improved 3rd party dialer launching experience.

Softare Engineer in Test II - Security Jan 2009 – Apr 2011

Worked with team to implement new algorithm to identify spam traits, improving performance by 90% and increasing maintainability.

Lead team of 3 test contractors. Implemented cross-datacenter tests to validate functionality.

Developed an internal tools to improve code documentation and status reporting.

Collaborated cross-team to develop filesystem and network scanner for private information.

Softare Engineer in Test

Mar 2008 – Dec 2008

Created automated testing for OneCare upgrade path and implemented repair improved tool to reduce support costs.

Global Roam | BRISBANE, QUEENSLAND, AUSTRALIA

Software Engineer

Nov 2006 - Feb 2008

Planned and developed an overhaul of user interface for the Ontario electricity market application.

### **AWARDS**

Microsoft Gold Star Award for excellence in leadership
Dean's Commendation for High Achievement at University for 7 consecutive semesters
Excellence in Tutoring Award and highest possible score in student survey
Cannon Information Systems Research of Australia University Sholarship

## **PROJECTS**

Chrome Extension | nickreynolds.net/projects/long-click-new-tab

An extension to allow users of laptops to easily open links in a background tab without using the context menu.

Phone Game | nickreynolds.net/projects/pen-and-paper

2D physics-based puzzle game built for Windows Phone 7 using the XNA Framework and the Box2D physics library.

Dynamic Note Taking Website | nickreynolds.net/projects/keepsit

A note keeping website built using PHP, MySql, CSS, HTML and JavaScript (using the JQuery library).